Alden Davidson

adavidson@pm.me 570-412-3528 adavidson.us

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineering professional with experience developing and designing applications using modern web technologies. Strong interest in continuous learning and using new tools to improve products and processes. Adept at developing and deploying full-stack solutions with a relentless and passionate focus on user outcomes.

SKILLS-

Languages & Tools: Azure Kubernetes Services, CSS, Docker, Git, Kotlin, Linux, LaTeX, React, React Native, Spring, SQL, TypeScript Practices: Continuous Integration, Extreme Programming, Test-Driven Development, User-Centered Design

WORK HISTORY

Feb 2024 - Current

SkillBridge Internship: Software Engineer

Sagely | Remote

- Built a social learning platform to guide users' personal and professional learning journeys, using TypeScript, React, and TailwindCSS.
- Integrated OpenAI's GPT using LangChain and Jina Reader to organize, curate, and contextualize user content
- Ensured feature parity on both web and mobile applications to create a consistent user experience

Jan 2022 - Feb 2024

Full-Stack Software Engineer

United States Space Force | Los Angeles, CA

- Developed and sustained two full-stack applications, using TypeScript, React, Kotlin, and Spring, to modernize satellite management for 1200+global users
- Transitioned two applications from Cloud Foundry to Azure Kubernetes Services as tracers for new pipeline and deployment environment
- Led scoping of project requested by USSF Chief of Space Operations to allocate satellite resources from multiple locations

Nov 2019 – Dec 2021

Project Manager

United States Space Force | Los Angeles, CA

- Planned, scheduled, and negotiated \$28M follow-on for \$34M project
- Monitored project performance to identify and implement improvements
- Supervised cross-functional team of 8 to manage project issues and risks
- Provided detailed project status updates to users, executive management, and other stakeholders

EDUCATION.

05/2019

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering

Rochester Institute of Technology | Rochester, NY